Medieval and Renaissance Manuscripts Collection - Library Special Collections, ca. 1198-1616
UCLA Library Special Collections
- The Charles E. Young Research Library: Department of Special Collections.
  - BIBLE, with prologues and additions. Spain, s. XIIImed., 170/348.; Fig. 13; Parchment, ff. i + 387 + i; 175 × 120 (122 × 77) mm. i 2(pastedown + flyleaf, numbered f. 1) 1-2116 2218(-18b) 2316 2416(+1) ii2 (back flyleaf, numbered f. 387 + pastedown; foliation includes f. 113bis and the halfsheet 
    3) ff. 286-354 bis: New Testament, f. 286 Prologus primus super Matheum [Stegmüller 589]; f. 286r-v Secundus prologus super Matheum [Stegmüller 590]; ff. 286v-295 Matheus evangelista [Stegmüller 47]; f. 295 Prologus Marchi evangeliste [Stegmüller 607]; ff. 295-300v Liber Marchi evangeliste [Stegmüller 48]; f. 300v Prologus in libro Luce evangeliste [Stegmüller 620]; ff. 300v-309v [Luc.], Quoniam quidem multi... eruditus es veritate. Incipit liber Luce evangeliste Fuit in diebus Herodis.., [Stegmüller 49]; f. 310 Prologus Iohannis evangeliste [Stegmüller 624]; ff. 310-317 Liber Iohannis evangeliste [Stegmüller 50]; f. 317 [Prologus in Pauli ep. ad Rom.; Stegmüller 670]; f. 317r-v Prefatio s. Iheronimi, Primum quidem intelligere nos oportet quibus aut qualibet... scripsisse, maxime cum nobis in his precepta et exempla videndi plenissime sint digesta. Sed initio nascentis ecclesie novis causis existentibus etiam post Romanis qui ex Iudeis et gentibus ... ad pacem et concordiam cohortatur [? + Stegmüller 674]; f. 317v Argumentum [Stegmüller 677 + 664]; ff. 317v-321 Epistola Pauli apostoli ad Romanos [Stegmüller 52]; f. 32] Argumentum Ieronimi [in I Cor.; Stegmüller 685]; ff. 321-324 Epistola prima ad Corinthios [Stegmüller 53]; f. 324 Argumentum [in II Cor.; Stegmüller 699]; ff. 324-326v Epistola secunda ad Chorintios [Stegmüller 54]; f. 326v Argumentum [in Gal.; Stegmüller 707]; ff. 326v-327v Epistola ad Galathas [Stegmüller 55]; f. 327v Argumentum [in Ephes; Stegmüller 715]; if. 327v-329 Epistola ad Ephesios [Stegmüller 56]; f. 329 Argumentum [in Philipp.; Stegmüller 728]; f. 329r-v Epistola ad Philippenses [Stegmüller 57]; ff. 329v-330 Argumentum [in Col.; Stegmüller 736]; f. 330r-v Epistola ad Colossenses [Stegmüller 58]; f. 330v Argumentum [in I Thess.; Stegmüller 747]; ff. 330v-331v Epistola prima ad Thessalonicenses [Stegmüller 59]; f. 331v Argumentum [in II Thess.; Stegmüller 752]; ff. 331v-332 Epistola secunda ad Thessalonicenses [Stegmüller 60]; f. 332 Argumentum [in I Tim.; Stegmüller 765]; ff. 332-333 Epistola Ia ad Timotheum [Stegmüller 61]; f. 333 Item prologus [in II Tim., Stegmüller 772]; f. 333r-v Epistola II ad Timotheum [Stegmüller 62]; f. 333v Argumentum [in Tit.; Stegmüller 780]; ff. 333v-334 Epistola ad Titum [Stegmüller 63]; f. 334 Argumentum [in Philem., Stegmüller 783]; f. 334 Epistola ad Philo [sic, for Philemonem, Stegmüller 64]; f. 334 Prologus in epistola ad Hebreos [Stegmüller 793]; ff. 334-337 Epistola ad Hebreos [Stegmüller 65]; f. 337 Prologus in Actibus apostolorum [Stegmüller 640]; f. 337 Item alius prologus [Stegmüller 639]; ff. 337-346 Liber Actuum apostolorum [Stegmüller 51]; f. 346 [Prologus in VII epist. canon.; Stegmüller 807, with variants]; f. 346 Prologus in Epistola Iacobi [Stegmüller 809 + 806]; ff. 346-347 Epistola Iacobi apostoli [Stegmüller 66]; f. 347 Prologus [in I Petr; Stegmüller 815]; ff. 347-348 Epistola prima Petri [Stegmüller 67]; f. 348 Prologus [in II Petr; Stegmüller 818]; f. 348r-v Epistola II Petri [Stegmüller 68]; f. 348v Prologus [in I Ioh.; Stegmüller 822]; ff. 348v-349v Epistola prima Iohannis [Stegmüller 69]; f. 349v Prologus [in II Ioh.; Stegmüller 823]; ff. 349v-350 Epistola secunda Iohannis [Stegmüller 70]; f. 350 Prologus [in III Ioh.; Stegmüller 824]; f. 350 Epistola III Iohannis [Stegmüller 71]; f. 350 Prologus [in Iudae; Stegmüller 825]; f. 350 Epistola Iude [Stegmüller 72]; f. 350r-v Prologus in libro Apocalipsis [Stegmüller 839]; ff. 350v-354bis Liber Apocalipsis [Stegmüller 73]; f. 354bisv blank; the outer column, excised, was probably blank.
    4) ff. 355-383v: [Stephen Langton, Interpretationes hebraicorum nominum] Aaz apprehendens vel apprehensio. Aad testificans vel testimonium... Zusithidis consilium vel consiliatrix. Zuzym consiliantes eos vel consiliatores eorum. Expliciunt interpretationes [Stegmüller 7709].
    5) ff. 383v-386v: [Summa contra hereticos et manicheos de articulis et sacramentis ecclesie, pts. 1 and 2, added by a thirteenth-century gothic bookhand] I°quod pater et filius et spiritus sanctus una substancia et unus Deus... f. 385 Incipit campilatio auctoritatum de sacramentis ecclesie contra hereticos manicheos... Explicit summa breviata contra manicheos paterinos et contra passaginos et circumcisos et contra multos alios hereticos qui nituntur subvertere veritatem quorum dampnatio iam olim non cessat et eorum perditio non dormitat de qua dampnatione ille custodiat suos qui ad dexteram maiestatis residet in excelsis super novem ordines angelorum [concluding with 19 additional topics ff. 385v-386v:] Probatio quod unus est Deus ... sic nos existimet homo ut ministros Christi.
    Concerning this work see Laura Light, “The New Thirteenth-Century Bible and the Challenge of Heresy,” Viator 18 (1987) 275-288; excerpts and a list of manuscripts, 287.
    6) f. 386v: [List of epistle and gospel lections of the temporale for feasts only] Dominica I a in adventu. Ro. xii [= xiii]. Scientes quia. Matthew xxi. Cum appropinquasset Ihesus... Dominica XXIIII [post oct. Pentec.] Colo. i. Non cessamus pro vobis. Matthew ix. Loquente Ihesus ad turbas. Dominica XXV, Ier. xxiii [.b., added]. Ecce dies ve(nit). Ioh. vi [.b., added]. Cum sublevasset oculos [added by a graceful thirteenth-century gothic bookhand].
    The readings agree with the Roman use, except the first reading for the last Sunday of the year; on the back pastedown a nineteenth- or twentieth-century hand notes: “The lectionary on the last leaf but one does not agree with Rome or Paris, but was common elsewhere both in France and England.”
    7) f. 387r-v: [Following from f. 1v, a list of epistle and gospel lections for the sanctorale] In vigilia sancti Andree apostoli. Eccli. xliiii.g. Benediccio Dei... [In natale unius virginis] Matthew xxv.a. Simili est regnum celorum fi. neque horam [added by the hand of f. 1r-v].
    Written in Spain in the middle of the thirteenth century. In the possession of a Dominican convent or friar before the end of the century; front pastedown top, half cropped, “... -ia ordinis predicatorum.” In England before the fourteenth century; English hands on ff. 1r-v, 387r-v, front pastedown. On f. 386 lower margin, erased note of accounts in fourteenth-century anglicana, “... sol[idos]... sol[idos]... Ego frater... sororem... sorores. ...” On f. 1v top, an erased note. Paper label “11” on the spine. Belonged to Isaac Foot; his bookplate, f. 1v. Came to UCLA with the Foot Collection (see above, p.39) in 1960.
    Secundo folio: plagis est decalogo
  - MARCO BONINO, SKETCHBOOK OF ENGINES; MISCELLANY. North Italy; France, s. XVI2, s. XVII2., 170/358.; Fig. 32
    - Part I.
      1) ff. 1-57: An engineer's sketchbook signed by Marco Bonino (”di Marco Bonino,” f.1) in the hand that writes the captions in Italian. ff. 1-2v, machines related to water—water-powered machines, boats and boat gear, water-lifting machines, canal blockades, floating bridges, machines for dredging canals; ff. 3-7v, weight-moving machines and construction equipment, bellows, perpetual motion machines; ff. 7v-8v, military devices; ff. 9-12v, architectural studies; f. 13 blank; ff. 13v-19v, cars, pulverizers, bell-ringing device, column-lifters and weight-moving machines; f. 20r-v, bellows; ff. 21-26v, construction equipment, clay scoops, anchor for the base of a crane, pile-drivers; ff. 26v-27, climbing devices; ff. 27v-29, flotation devices, bailers, water wheels; ff. 29v-30v, windmills, clockwork, grappling hooks; ff. 31-32, fasteners for binding ropes together, ladder erectors, a rotisserie turned by heat rising from its fire; ff. 32v-51, water- and man-powered mills, pumps, pistons, gears; ff. 51-57, machines relating to water and military devices: floating canal blockades, retrieval baskets, devices for sinking enemy ships, boats with covers to protect rowers, ff. 57v-58 blank.
      About 400 engineering drawings, adapted or copied from various sources, particularly from the fifteenth-century Italian engineers Francesco di Giorgio Martini (1439-1501) and Mariano Taccola (1381-1458?). Some drawings, or elements of drawings, have no known source and may originate with Bonino; these include the water-pump details on ff. 42v-43v, and the clockwork on f. 29v which incorporates a loosely coiled spring. An extensive typewritten report on the manuscript, written by Silvio A. Bedini, is available in the Department of Special Collections.
      2) f. 58v: Archimedean screw water-lift, and hasp with padlock, signed by a French hand and dated 1612; this has been added on the blank verso of the last folio in Bonino's manuscript.
    - Part II.
      f. 59 blank.
      3) ff. 59v-60: Sketches of plumbing, valves, and geared wheels, watercolored in blue, with captions in French, f. 60v blank.
      4) f. 60bis r-v, a loose leaf of only half width: Sketch of a cannon, with description and explanation in French, in the hand of F. de Vegnauld (cf. f. 62); this is a formal rendering of the rough sketch on f. 61.
      5) f. 61: Hasty sketch, with brief notes in rapid cursive, for the formal drawing on f. 60bis f. 61v blank.
      6) f. 62: Trompette pour se parler de 1/2 ligue[?] inventée par Mr. Morland Anglois, [signed] F. de Vegnauld fecit. 30a Ianuarii anni MDCLXXIII [same hand as f. 60bis, etc.], f. 62v blank.
      A detailed drawing of the speaking trumpet invented in 1670 by Samuel Morland, Master Mechanic to King Charles II. F. de Vegnauld's notes record that he himself had experimented with a similar device in 1672.
      7) f. 63: A mechanized chariot or cart sketched in crayon; f. 63v blank; an inserted foldout.
      8) ff. 64-66: Machinery sketched in ink. f. 66v blank, ff. 65-66 are inserted foldouts.
      9) f. 67: An inserted engraving of a bell-ringing mechanism; f. 67v, dedication to Fr. Pierre Rossilhe, rector of the Jesuit College at Tournon 1591-1596 and 1600-1605.
      10) ff. 69 and 70: Late sixteenth-century Italian engineering drawings, in black ink on brownish paper, captions (in the same hand) in Latin and Italian respectively, pasted on the folios, ff. 69v and 70v blank.
      11) ff. 70v-71: Sketch in ink of a pump, accompanied by an extensive French text in the hand of F. de Vegnauld, “Aoust 1680. Pompe nouvelle... .” ff. 71v-83v blank.
      Pt. 1 was written in the late sixteenth century in northern Italy, as the language suggests, by Marco Bonino. In France by 1612; note on f. 58v. Pt. 2 was compiled in the late seventeenth century by F. de Vegnauld, who combined the two parts and had them bound; the front flyleaves belong to the same batch of paper on which de Vegnauld wrote. Purchased by UCLA from H.P. Kraus, New York, in 1964.
      L. Reti, “The Double-Acting Principle in East and West,” Technology and Culture vol.11 (1970) pp.193-194, with pictures off. 20r-v.
      UCLA Librarian vol.26 (1973) pp.7-8, with pictures.
      A copy of this book is UCLA Negative Microfilm no.02342.
  - REPORTS OF VENETIAN AMBASSADORS 1558-1570, CONCLAVES 1590 AND 1623. Italy, s. XVI/XVII and XVII1., *170/380.
    - Part 1.
      1) ff. 1-33: Relatione del clarissimo messer Michel Soriano ritornato ambasciatore da Filippo Re di Spagna l'anno 1560, Serenissimo Principe, Padri e Signori eccelentissimi, l'opinione universale et provato con esperienza..., con altro che con la gratia della Serenità vostra e delle Signorie vostre eccellentissime. II fine. f. 33v blank.
      E. Alberi, ed., Le relazioni degli ambasciatori veneti al Senato duranle il secolo decimosesto ser.1, vol.3 (Florence, 1853) pp.333-90.
      2) ff. 34-62v: Relatione del clarissimo messer Bernardo Navagero che fu poi cardinale alla Republica sua di Venetia tornando di Roma ambasciatore a Papa Paolo IIII l'anno 1558, Ho imparato, Serenissimo Principe, nelle legationi... che io non accetti allegramente. II fine.
      Alberi, Le relazioni... ser.2, vol.3 (Florence, 1856) pp.369-416.
      3) ff. 63v-96: Relatione del clarissimo messer Giovan Cornero tornato ambasciatore dal Re di Francia l'anno MDLXX, Ho veduto il regno di Francia... ma affettuosa et sincera servitù mia. II fine.
      Cf. N. Tommaseo. Relations des ambassadeurs vénitiens sur les affaires de France au XVIe siècle 2 (Paris, 1838).
      4) ff. 97-138: Conclave di Papa Gregorio XIIII nel quale si racconta destintamente tutte l'attioni che sono in esso occorse nell'anno 1590, Giusto desiderio veramente et laudabil' curiosità èquella che V. S. mostra d'haver particolar' ragguaglio... il discorso e la prudenza civile. II fine. ff. 138v-140v blank.
    - Part 2.
      5) ff. 141-146v: [Faculties and duties of the nuncio in Naples] II Nuntio di Napoli ha titolo di Nuntio... all'arcivescovo che obedisca.
    - Part 3., 3 parts together by the seventeenth century: Paper, ff. i + 199; 270 × 195 mm. Gatherings of mostly 10 leaves in part 1; catchwords at the bottom verso of each folio in pts. 1-3. ca.25 long lines; unruled. Written by several professional Italian cursive hands.; Bound in limp cardboard backed in parchment, s. XVII.
      6) ff. 147-189: [Conclave for the election of Urban VIII] Fatte secondo l'antica consuetudine l'essequie al morto pontefice Gregorio XV li cardinali la mattina 19 luglio 1623... de privati interessi e dissentioni. ff. 189v-199v blank.
      Written in Italy, part 1 after 1590 possibly in Venice, pts. 2 and 3 (after 1623) early in the seventeenth century. Purchased by UCLA from B. Rosenthal in New York in 1964.
  - JACOBUS DE VORAGINE, SERMONES DE TEMPORE, with additions. Italy, s. XIV2., 170/382.; Parchment, ff. i (modern) + 391 (foliated 1-388, with 45bis, 213bis, 301bis, ) + i (modern); 148 × 105 (93 × 68; fols. 381-387, 100 × 68) mm. 1-312 412+1 5-912108 11-1812 194 20-3112 3210 348. Plain horizontal catchwords in the center of the lower margin. 2 columns of 31 lines (fols. 381-387, 26/34 lines); ruled in lead, double bounding lines. Written in a small round Italian gothic bookhand (littera textualis); ink varies from grayish brown to greenish. On f. 1, a 2-line illuminated pink and blue initial with a border of pink and blue stylized floral patterns in the inner and part of the upper and lower margins; 2-line initials alternately red on blue penwork and blue on red; initials sometimes slashed with red; paragraph marks alternately red and blue; titles in red minuscule, inconsistent in numbering the Sundays of the liturgical year. The sermons on the Transfiguration that fill the last 2½ columns of quire 33 and the added quire 34 (ff. 380rb-387v) are a slightly later addition in a rounded script that expands letters more in width than in height; minims show a tendency to be broken; the a is flat-topped and squarish; the tironian 7 appears both crossed and uncrossed; top and bottom lines show long ascenders and descenders with chancery flourishes slashed with red; strong French influence is seen in the red and blue penwork extending from top to bottom margin, esp. ff. 383v, 386v, 387v. Many marginal notes throughout the codex by three or more contemporary or slightly later cursive gothic hands, one of which has carefully corrected the text.; Bound in wooden boards backed in leather with diagonal rules and traces of two clasps, s. XIX.
    1) ff. 1-116v: Incipiunt sermones dominicales de evangelio per totum annum editi a fratre Iacoba de Veragine [sic] ordinis fratrum predicatorum archiepiscopo Ianuensi; ff. 1 -3v Dominica prima de adventu [Schneyer no.2]; ff. 3v-6 De eadem [= dom. 2; Schneyer no.5]; ff. 6-8 Dominica secunda [= tertia] de adventu [Schneyer no.8]; ff. 8-10 Dominica 3 [= 4] de adventu [Schneyer no.11]; ff. 10-11 Dominica 4 de adventu, Anno quinto decimo etc. Luc. 3. [1]. Volens ostendere qui recipiant verbum allocutionis interne describit hic tres differentias hominum.. Ps. ecce elongavi fugiens etc.; ff. 11-13 De eadem, Factum est verbum domini super loannem Zacharie filium in deserto [Luc. 3.2], Describens evangelista initia nascentis ecclesie ponit quattuor scilicet: causam principaliter operantem, personam, locum et actum... Baruch 4. Delicati mei ambulaverunt vias asperas; ff. 13-15 De eadem, Videbit omnis caro salutare Dei. Luc. 3. [6]. Verbum istud est evangelicum quia in evangelio scriptum est et propheticum quia de propheta Ys. 40 sumptum. In quo pronuntiatur salvatoris adventus... vel triumphus, vel regnum, vel iudicium, vel reversio. Rogamus Deum etc.; ff. 15-17 Dominica infra octavam natalis Domini [Schneyer no.14]; ff. 17-19 Dominica infra octavam epyphanie [Schneyer no.17]; ff. 19-21 Dominica 2 4 post epyphaniam [Schneyer no.20]; ff. 21-23v Dominica 3 post epyphaniam [Schneyer no.23]; ff. 23v-24 Dominica 4 post epyphaniam, Ascendente Ihesu in naviculam secuti sunt eum discipuli eius. Matthew 8. [23]. Sepe contingit quod [interlin, quando] quis penitentiam inchoat temptatio eum pulsat... voce corvina quia noluerunt [ signe de renvoi, contemporary marginal note: “hunc sermonem completum require in fine libri istius scilicet 379” (= f. 378v); Schneyer no.26]; ff. 24-26 Sermo secundus [title and first lines added in the lower margin, continues in the body; Schneyer no.27]; ff. 26-28v Dominica V a post epyphaniam [Schneyer no.29]; ff. 28v-31 Dominica in septuagesima,... quod sic murmurent taliter respondetur eis [beginning like Schneyer no.32]; ff. 31-33v Dominica in sexagesima [Schneyer no.35]; ff. 33v-36v Dominica in quinquagesima [Schneyer no.38]; ff. 36vb-39 Dominica in octava pasche [Schneyer no.62]; ff. 39-42 Dominica 2a post resurrectionem [Schneyer no.65]; ff. 42-44v Dominica 3a post pentecosten [= resurrectionem], ... a societate fastidium quia sicientes saciabuntur et satiati sitiemus [beginning like Schneyer 68]; ff. 44v-45 bisv Dominica 4a post resurrectionem [Schneyer no.71; the text on the added f. 45r-v is marked for insertion at f. 45 bis rb]; ff. 45bis v-48v Dominica Va post resurrectionem [Schneyer no.74]; ff. 48v-51 Dominica infra octavam ascensionis [Schneyer no.77]; ff. 51-53v In pentecosten [Schneyer no.80]; ff. 53v-56 Dominica in trinitate [Schneyer no.83]; ff. 56-59 Dominica prima post pentecosten [Schneyer no.86]; ff. 59-62 Dominica 2 apost pentecosten [Schneyer no.89]; ff. 62-64v Dominica 3 a post pentecosten [Schneyer no.92]; ff. 64v-67v Dominica prima [= quarta] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.95]; ff. 67v-69v Dominica 4 [= 5] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.98], ff. 69v-71v Dominica V[= VI] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.101 ]; ff. 71v-74 Dominica 6 [= 7] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.104]; ff. 74-76v Dominica 7 [= 8] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.107]; ff. 76v-78 Dominica 8 [= 9] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.110]; ff. 78-80v Dominica 9 [= 10] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.113]; ff. 80v-82v Dominica X [= XI ] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.116]; ff. 82v-85 Dominica 11 [= 12] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.119]; ff. 85-87 Dominica 12 [= 13] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.122]; ff. 87-89v Dominica 13 [= 14] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.125]; ff. 89v-92 Dominica 14 [= 15] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.128]; ff. 92-95 Dominica 15 [= 16] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.131]; ff. 95-97v Dominica 16 [= 17] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.134]; ff. 97v-99v Dominica 17 [= 18] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.137]; ff. 99v-102 Dominica 18 [= 19] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.140]; ff. 102-104v Dominica 19 [= 20] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.143]; ff. 104v-107 Dominica 20 [= 21] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.146]; ff. 107-109v Dominica XXI [= XXII] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.149]; ff. 109v-112 Dominica 22 [= 23] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.152]; ff. 112-114v Dominica 23 [= 24] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.155]; ff. 114v-116v Dominica 5 in quadragesima [= 25 post pentecosten, Schneyer no.158].
    2) ff. 117-215v [A second annual cycle]; ff. 117-118v Dominica prima de adventu [Schneyer no.3]; ff. 118v-120v Dominica prima [= secunda] de adventu [Schneyer no.6]; ff. 120v-122v Dominica 2 [= 3] de adventu [Schneyer no.9]; ff. 122-124 [guide letters i.m., Dominica 3a ( = 4a) de adventu; Schneyer no.12]; ff. 124-125v Dominica infra octavam nativitatis [Schneyer no.15]; ff. 125v-127v Dominica infra octavam epyphanie [Schneyer no.18]; ff. 127v-129 Dominica prima octava epyphanie [= secunda post epiphaniam; Schneyer no.21]; ff. 129-131 Dominica 2a [= 3a] post epyfaniam [Schneyer no.24]; ff. 131-133 Dominica 3 [= 4] post epyphaniam [Schneyer no.28]; ff. 133-135v Dominica 4 [= 5] post octavam epyphanie. [Schneyer no.30]; ff. 135v-138 Dominica in septuagesima sermo [Schneyer no.33]; ff. 138-140v Dominica in sexagesima [Schneyer no.36]; ff. 140v-142v Dominica in quinquagesima sermo [Schneyer no.39]; ff. 142v-145 Dominica prima post pasca [Schneyer no.63]; ff. 145-147v Dominica 2a post pasca [Schneyer no.66]; ff. 147v-150v Dominica 3a post pascha [Schneyer no.69]; ff. 150v-152v Dominica 4 post pascha [Schneyer no.72]; ff. 152v-154v Dominica 5 post pentecosten [= pascha; Schneyer no.76]; ff. 154v-156v Dominica in octava ascensionis [Schneyer no.78]; ff. 156v-159 Dominica pentecostis [Schneyer no.81]; ff. 159-161v Dominica de trinitate [Schneyer no.84]; ff. 161v-164 Dominica prima post pentecosten [Schneyer no.87]; ff. 164-166v Dominica 2 post pentecosten [Schneyer no.90]; ff. 166v-168v Dominica 3 post pentecosten [Schneyer no.93]; ff. 168v-171 Dominica prima [= quarta] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.96]; ff. 171-172v Dominica 4 [= 5] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.99]; ff. 172v-174v Dominica 5a [= 6a] post pentecosten,... sibi subiciat tamquam domina ancillam suam [beginning like Schneyer 102]; ff. 174v-176v Dominica 6 [= 7] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.105]; ff. 176v-178v Dominica 7 [= 8] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.108]; ff. 178v-180v Dominica 8 [= 9] post pentecosten [Schneyer no.111]; ff. 180v-182v Dominica 9 [= 10]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.114]; ff. 182v-184v [guide letters, Dominica X( = XI)post pentecosten; Schneyer no.117]; ff. 184v-186v Dominica 11 [= 12]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.120]; ff. 186v-188v Dominica 12 [= 13]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.123]; ff. 188v-191 [Dominica 14 post pentecosten; Schneyer no.126]; ff. 191-193v Dominica 14 [= 15]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.129]; ff. 193v-195v Dominica 15 [= 16]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.132]; ff. 195v-198 Dominica 16 [= 17]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.135]; ff. 198-200v Dominica 17 [= 18]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.138]; ff. 200v-202 Dominica 18 [= 19]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.141]; ff. 202-204v Dominica 19 [= 20]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.144]; ff. 204v-207 Dominica [20, add. = 21 ]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.147]; ff. 207-209v Dominica 21 [= 22]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.150]; ff. 209v-211v Dominica 22 [= 23]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.153]; ff. 211v-213bis Dominica 23 [= 24]post pentecosten [Schneyer no.156]; ff. 213bis-215v Dominica 4 in quadragesima [= 25 post pentecosten; Schneyer no.159].